The Boy and The Organ Upon That Day}
Yomogi Preschool}
Hanato Kobato, Private Eye.}
Under the blue, under the
blue, under the big blue sky.
The river, the river, the river feeds the fluffy grass.
Let’s go play hide and seek, in a field of sunflowers.
Go and fly, high in the sky, you round and shiny soap bubbles.
Go and chase, go and chase.
Go and chase the snow white… clouds.
Run along, run along.
Together with all your friends.
It’s hot as hell and you’re still up this early, doing stuff!
What kind of song is that anyway?
Everybody at Yomogi Preschool learned that song! It’s very fun!
High upon the mountaintop-
Huh?
Oh, that was terrifying!
I thought I was going to fall!
Quiet down over there!
Oh, good morning!
What are you doing up so early on a Sunday?
I-I’m airing out my futon!
The weather’s so nice today…
Geez. Can’t you do anything without making a ruckus?
He’s mean.
Do… ba… to…
Ioryogi-san! Are you all right?
Am I all right…?
Hell no!
I told you! I’m a stuffed animal, dammit!
Don’t treat me so rough!
I’m sorry!
I’m leaving.
I’ll see you later. Stay safe.
Okay.
So Chitose-san is seeing Fujimoto-san off.
Looks like it.
It’s strange.
What is?
Fujimoto-san was just next door
in his room, and now he’s leaving.
He’s sure got a lot on his plate.
Could it be…?
Hm?
That Fujimoto-san is in two places at once?
This is not a damn mystery novel!
Kobato-san?! What was that noise?
It was nothing!
Where’re you going?
Yomogi Preschool.
But you’re off today.
Since it’s such good weather,
I’m going to air out the futons!
Hey, Kobato, do you even get it?
Get what?
The reason why you came here.
To fill the bottle full of confetti!
If you do get it, then there has to be other stuff for you to do. Especially on a Sunday!
Hmm, but…
Right now…
…I want to be of use to Yomogi
Preschool. Even if it’s a little bit.
I’m to inform you that the previous head of Yomogi Preschool,
appears to have been tricked into taking out a loan.
The previous head?
Yes. Okiura Sayaka’s father, but he died two years ago.
The trickster is a pretty dangerous fellow, and it involves a close relative of Okiura Sayaka.
Sayaka-sensei?
Kobato-chan?
What’s the matter? Today’s your day off.
Yes!
I’ve come to air out everyone’s futon!
Futons?
Yes! Since it’s such wonderful weather we have outside!
The weather is beautiful.
I didn’t even notice.
Okay. Let’s air them out together.
Yes!
Chitose is really pleased.
She says she’s glad to have such a
wonderful girl like you living there.
I also really enjoy being with
Chitose-san, Chiho-chan and Chise-chan!
And what about your neighbor, Fujimoto-kun?
Has he… been mean to you?
Fujimoto-san has been mean
to me, but sometimes he’s not.
I don’t understand.
What kind of person is he?
Fujimoto-kun is actually quite kind.
He has been ever since he was little.
A little Fujimoto-san?
I can’t imagine that at all!
Care to see?
Sorry to keep you waiting. I found it.
Here.
He was so small!
Is that really Fujimoto-san?
Yes. That picture was taken the
day Fujimoto-kun first came here.
So Fujimoto-san was a student at Yomogi Preschool?
Nope. Not at all.
Fujimoto-kun…
…was an orphan.
Orphan?
What is an orphan?
It is a child that doesn’t have
a mother, a father, or any family.
If you aren’t willing to care for it to the end, then leave it alone.
You’ll never feel complete if you only do things for your own satisfaction.
You’re just as bad as the person who abandoned it.
So that’s why…
…he said those things.
Kobato-chan?
Tell me more!
I want to know even more about Fujimoto-san when he was little!
Understood.
It was maybe 14 years ago.
My father, you see, he took in Fujimoto-kun.
I’m home, Sayaka.
This is the boy I told you about, Fujimoto Kiyokazu-kun.
Kiyokazu-kun. This is my daughter, Sayaka.
I’m Sayaka. Nice to meet you, Kiyokazu-kun.
Oh, a picture! Let’s take a keepsake picture!
I’ll go get the camera.
Camera… camera…
Here we go…
Yomogi Preschool has a… “gi!”
From that day on, Fujimoto-kun has been coming here.
Fujimoto-san looks mad.
He sure does! He always had that
face when he was first settling in here.
He never spoke to anyone.
Not even to you, Sayaka-sensei?
Yeah… He always kept to himself.
I tried introducing him to the kids.
They were all very interested in him at first.
But since he wouldn’t play with them,
they soon distanced themselves from him.
He didn’t seem to have any friends at his school either.
It seemed that no one was close to him personally,
and that there was no way to help him.
Welcome back!
You’re supposed to say “I’m back!”
I hate Kiyokazu-kun!
Me too.
Sayaka-chan, bye-bye!
Bye-bye! I’ll see you tomorrow!
Kiyokazu-kun… do you like the organ?
Kiyokazu-kun!
Sayaka-chan!
Bye-bye! I’ll see you tomorrow!
Bye-bye!
Come on!
Let’s hurry!
Fujimoto-san…
Nice, cold beer!
We’re now giving it out for free!
Can I have one?
Sure, go ahead!
Would you like a nice beer?
We’re on a product campaign!
Excuse me.
May I have that?
Uh, yes. It’s a new product.
Go ahead and try it.
Thank you very much.
Shuichiro-san will surely be pleased.
It was a…
…beautiful summer day, much like today.
It’s my turn next!
No, it’s my turn!
You’ve already had your turn, Kuri-chan!
Hey, hey, no fighting. Take your turns.
Okay!
Will they start blooming soon?
They will.
Because you all did such good job caring for them, they will bloom beautifully.
Really?
Honest!
Yay!
Okay, kids. Let’s clean up so we can go play.
Okay!
Welcome back.
Tomo-chan, are you all right?
You see, a ball whooshed in, and Tomo-chan got scared and fell!
Sayaka-chan!
Tomo-chan, did you hurt yourself anywhere?
Are you all right?
Ow!
Dude, why did you push me?
My bad, man!
I didn’t think you’d actually fall!
Up yours! Dang, now I’m all messed up!
Screw that, hurry up and find the ball!
You’re the one that couldn’t handle the pass!
All right, geez.
Dammit, it won’t come out.
Why’s this place wet anyway?
Hey!
What do you two think you’re doing?
Uh, we lost a ball here.
That was dangerous! You could have hit a child!
No one got hit! Why go ballistic?
Get out of the flower bed now!
What?
The kids planted those sunflowers,
and tended them with all their hearts!
Now they’re just waiting for them to bloom!
Here’s your ball!
Now apologize to this girl, the kids,
and then get out!
W-We apologize.
Sorry.
Don’t you know how to tame a ball?
You should quit passing from the wrong places!
Sayaka-chan…
What about the sunflower?
Don’t worry.
It’s just a little hurt.
You just tie it down like this…
And if you water it every day, I’m sure it will bloom.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
Go and chase, go and chase.
Go and chase the snow white clouds.
Run along, run along. Together with all your friends.
High upon the mountaintop you can see everything.
Let us find, let us find, let us find a new miracle.
You know how Fujimoto-kun is always working several jobs?
Yes.
He delivers pizza on a bicycle, delivers newspapers, plus a whole lot more.
He does that much?
Yes.
He puts in that work so he can contribute in paying off the preschool’s debts.
For this preschool?
That’s right.
He also says he’ll become an attorney.
He seems to stay up every night studying.
I really worry about his health.
It’s soft and fluffy and smells so nice!
That’s the smell of the sun.
The sun?
That’s right.
When you air out futons, they’ll smell like the sun.
Well, at least that what my dad told me.
Then tomorrow we’ll all take an
afternoon nap together with the sun!
That’s right.
Um, did I say something strange?
No, absolutely not. It sounded wonderful.
Yes, I can’t wait until tomorrow!
All right, let’s finish taking these down.
Yes!
Thanks for today. Be careful on your way back.
Yes! I’ll see you tomorrow.
The sun, huh?
Kiyokazu-kun, welcome back!
Come on, play the organ!
Yeah! Play it, play it!
It’s Kiyokazu!
You’re right!
Welcome back!
I’m…
I’m back.
Come on, Kiyokazu! The organ, the organ!
Come on, hurry!
We can see, we can see, we can see the red sunset.
Steadily, steadily, we steadily walk faraway.
If tomorrow’s a sunny day.
Let’s come back and play again.
Let us go, let us go, our homes are over there.
See? You got absolutely zilch!
But, but I aired out the futons.
I was able to help the preschool.
Yeah, and I was aired out along with them!
I’m sorry.
Kobato-san? Ioryogi-san?
I knew it was you two!
I’m glad I caught you two.
I was thinking you could have this.
You… you mean it?
Of course. Shuichiro-san’s share is in the refrigerator.
Then don’t mind if I do!
That’s great, Ioryogi-san.
All right, time to chug it down!
Wait a sec! I’ll just hold off on this now and drink it before bedtime!
Kohaku-san, I’m impressed at how you always take care to water the trees in your yard.
Other than this, there is nothing else I can do for Shuichiro-san.
But I am very glad I can be somewhat useful.
I’m also very glad when I can do
something useful for Yomogi Preschool.
Right! It makes one very happy to be useful for someone special.
Someone special?
Yomogi Preschool is a very
special place for Fujimoto-san.
That’s right. He holds down several jobs at once just for that place.
It’s exactly…
…how I feel.
Huh?
Yomogi Preschool is also very special to me.
I want to do my best to be useful for Sayaka-sensei and everyone else!
I will do my best!
Looks like you’ll still be doing things your own, wrong, way.
Welcome back, Kobato-san.
Welcome!
Welcome back!
I am home!
Oh, Fujimoto-san!
You were so cute when you were little!
Huh?
Also you were ever so passionate about playing the organ!
How did you know about that?!
Sayaka-sensei showed me some pictures today!
I want to see them!
Me too!
I also want to see Kiyokazu-kun as a kid.
Chitose-san, you too?
And he was so small, so cute and all pouty!
Stop talking!
I want to hear this!
Um, what should I do…
All right, we’ll wait until Kiyokazu-kun is gone.